<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- Chapters -->
<framexml>
<data>
<creditData>
			<![CDATA[© Oxford University Press 2013<br><br>All rights reserved. No part of this publication may be reproduced, <br>stored in a retrieval system, or transmitted, in any form or by any means,<br>without the prior permission in writing from Oxford University Press.<br><br><br><b>Acknowledgements</b><br><br><b>Photographs:</b> lizard: courtesy Jon Sullivan; seal: courtesy Frank Hurley; walrus: courtesy Max Smith; Amazon Rainforest: courtesy Roosevelt Garcia; leopard: courtesy Marie-Lan Nguyen; Pygmies: courtesy South Carolina Library; wolf: courtesy Trisha M Shears; rock salt: courtesy Mark A. Wilson; magnesite, soapstone: courtesy Dave Dyet; Army Welfare Trust building: courtesy Shariq Iqbal Rai; Quetta city: courtesy Maqsood Shah; Afghan man: courtesy Tripalis; Ahmed Shah Durrani: courtesy Colonel Gentil; Beijing Botanical Garden: courtesy Daderot; River Ganges: courtesy Steve Evans; markhor: courtesy Dave Pape; Asif Ali Zardari: courtesy Lawrence Jackson; bear, frog, coniferous forest, pine tree, spruce tree, oil seeds, lynx, barrage, gypsum, barite, sulphur, Allama Iqbal Airport Lahore, Gandhara Buddha statue, Ayatollah Khomeini, rice fields, Deccan Plateau, India Gate at New Delhi, The Holy Ka’aba, The Holy Quran, Great Mosque of Kufa, All India Muslim League, All India Muslim Educational Conference, Nawab Viqarul Mulk, Bahadur Shah Zafar, Indian National Congress: courtesy Wikimedia Commons <br><br>Developed by Sterco Digitex Pvt Limited <br>e-mail:<a href="mailto:info@stercodigitex.com"><font color="#FFFFFF"><U>info@stercodigitex.com</U></font></a>,web: <a href="http://www.stercodigitex.com"><font color="#FFFFFF"><U>www.stercodigitex.com</U></font></a><br><br>Published by Oxford University Press <br>No. 38, Sector 15, Korangi Industrial Area<BR>PO Box 8214, Karachi-74900, Pakistan<br><a href="http://www.oup.com.pk/"><font color="#FFFFFF"><U>www.oup.com/pk</U></font></a>]]>
</creditData>
</data>
</framexml>  