<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<framexml>
<data>

<!-- 1M2 -->
<text><![CDATA[<B>Some important cities</B>]]></text>

<text1><![CDATA[Pakistan does not have many large cities.]]></text1>
<text><![CDATA[Islamabad, the capital of Pakistan, is a new, planned city located at the base of the Margalla Hills.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Islamabad is the seat of the government.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Islamabad has a population of about 9 00 000.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Shah Faisal Mosque, one of the largest mosques in the world, is located in Islamabad.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The Supreme Court, the Secretariat, and the Quaid-e-Azam University are some well-known buildings in Islamabad.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Karachi is the largest city of Pakistan and was the capital of Pakistan before 1959.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Karachi grew from a small village to a major port due to the natural harbour at Keamari.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In the 19<font face="GG Superscript">th</font> century, the British made major developments to the city of Karachi.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The mausoleum of the Quaid-e-Azam is located in Karachi.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The National Museum of Pakistan, Pakistan Maritime Museum, and the beaches at Clifton and Sandspit are some other landmarks of Karachi.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Lahore is an ancient city on the eastern bank of the River Ravi.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Lahore came under Muslim rule in the 11<font face="GG Superscript">th</font> century.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[After independence in 1947, Lahore became the capital of the Punjab province.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Minar-e-Pakistan and the tombs of Jahangir and Nur Jehan are located in Lahore.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Rawalpindi is a major city on the Grand Trunk Road between Peshawar and Lahore.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Rawalpindi is one of the oldest settlements along the Khyber-Peshawar-Lahore route.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Rawalpindi is now the headquarters of the Pakistan Armed Forces.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Rawalpindi is also an important trading centre with a population of over 3 million.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Peshawar is the capital of Khyber Pakhtunkhwa.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Peshawar is the gateway between Central Asia and the subcontinent.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The word 'Quetta' comes from a Pushto word <i>Kwatta</i> which means 'fort'.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Quetta is situated at a height of 1700 metres.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Quetta is situated at a height of 1700 metres.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Quetta serves as an important road junction with routes leading into Afghanistan and Iran.]]></text>


<!-- Caption -->
<text><![CDATA[Islamabad]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Supreme Court of Pakistan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Karachi]]></text>
<mnj><![CDATA[Keamari Port]]></mnj>
<text><![CDATA[Beach in Karachi]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Allama Iqbal Airport in Lahore]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Lahore Fort]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Minar-e-Pakistan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Tomb of Jahangir]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Tomb of NurJehan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Rawalpindi]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Qissa Khawani Bazaar in Peshawar]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Gandhara culture]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Gandhara culture]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Quetta is the capital of Balochistan.]]></text>








</data>
</framexml>