<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<framexml>
<data>

<!-- 1M2 -->
<text><![CDATA[<B>Early history of Islam</B>]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[After the Prophet Muhammad <FONT SIZE="16" COLOR="">(PBUH)</FONT> passed away in 632 <FONT SIZE="16" COLOR="">CE</FONT>, his father-in-law, Hazrat Abu Bakr (RA) was chosen as the leader of the Muslims by the people of Madina.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Hazrat Abu Bakr (RA) became the first of the four Rightly-Guided Caliphs of the Muslims in 632.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Hazrat Abu Bakr (RA) suppressed many revolts and united Arabia.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Hazrat Umar Ibn al-Khattab (RA) became the second caliph in 634.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Muslims took control of Jerusalem, Palestine, Persia, and Khorasan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Under Hazrat Umar (RA), Islam spread further into Syria, Iraq, and Egypt.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Hazrat Umar (RA) is known for his able administration and the spread of Islam.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[Hazrat Usman Ibn Affan (RA) became the third caliph in 644.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Islam spread as far as Cyprus during the time of Hazrat Usman (RA).]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Hazrat Usman (RA) was martyred by some people who strongly disagreed with some of his decisions.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The work of completing the compilation of the Holy Quran was done during the caliphate of Hazrat Usman (RA).]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[Hazrat Ali (RA), the son-in-law of Hazrat Muhammad <FONT SIZE="16" COLOR="">(PBUH)</FONT> became the fourth caliph in 656.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Hazrat Ali (RA) had to spend a lot of time trying to stop his followers from fighting with each other.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Hazrat Ali (RA) moved the capital to Kufa in Iraq to solve the problems of different groups.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Hazrat Ali (RA) was martyred in 661.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[None of the caliphs that came after Hazrat Ali (RA) were as strong and powerful as the first four Caliphs.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Due to various disagreements between Muslims, two major groups&#x2014;Sunnis and Shiites&#x2014;came into being.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The Umayyad dynasty began in 662 with Amir Muawiya Ibn Abu Sufyan as the caliph after Hazrat Ali (RA).]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[During the Umayyad period, Muslim influence spread eastward into the subcontinent with Mohammad bin Qasim.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[Muslim rule was established in North Africa and Spain under Tariq.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The first large invasion of the subcontinent from the north-west was by Mahmud, the ruler of Ghazni.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[Mohammad Ghori established Islamic rule in the subcontinent.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Qutbuddin Aibak, the successor of Mohammad Ghori, conquered the whole of north India and set up the Delhi Sultanate.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Islam and its culture became a part of everyday life in the region.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The spread of Islam reached its peak under the Mughal rule in the subcontinent.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In the west, many battles were fought between the Muslims and Christians for the control of Jerusalem.]]></text>


<!-- Caption -->
<text><![CDATA[Arabia]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Grave of Hazrat Usman(RA)]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The Holy Quran]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The Great Mosque of Kufa]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sultan Mahmud of Ghazni]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Mohammad Ghori]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Qutb Minar in New Delhi]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Mughal Emperor Akbar]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Jerusalem]]></text>

</data>
</framexml>