<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<framexml>
<data>

<!-- 1M2 -->
<text><![CDATA[<B>After independence, 1947-71 and Pakistan since 1971</B>]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Quaid-e-Azam Mohammed Ali Jinnah became the governor general of independent Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Liaquat Ali Khan became the first prime minister.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Quaid-e-Azam Mohammed Ali Jinnah died in Karachi on 11 September 1948.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Liaquat Ali Khan was shot dead on 16 October 1951 in Rawalpindi.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The first constitution of Pakistan was passed in 1956.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Major General Iskander Mirza was the first president of Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[General Ayub Khan came to power after Iskander Mirza.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In 1969, due to strikes, Ayub Khan handed over control to General Mohammad Yahya Khan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The Awami League led by Sheikh Mujibur Rahman became a powerful party in East Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The Pakistan People's Party formed by Zulfikar Ali Bhutto became powerful in West Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[As Sheikh Mujib's party had an overall majority in the National Assembly, they made certain demands which the other party did not agree to.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In 1970, Sheikh Mujib was arrested and imprisoned.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The people of East Pakistan wanted to form their own country and rebelled.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[On 16 December 1971, Dhaka fell to Indian troops and a new country called Bangladesh came into being.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[With the formation of Bangladesh, West Pakistan became known as Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[A new constitution was passed on 14 August 1973.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In 1977, General Zia-ul-Haq came to power as Zulfikar Ali Bhutto became unpopular.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Zulfikar Ali Bhutto was tried and sentenced to death, which was carried out in April 1979.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[General Zia died in a plane crash on 17 August 1988.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In December 1988, Benazir Bhutto, the daughter of Zulfikar Ali Bhutto, became the first woman prime minister of Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In 1997, Nawaz Sharif became the prime minister of Pakistan during the midterm elections.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In 1990, Benazir's government was dismissed by the president Ghulam Ishaq Khan, and Nawaz Sharif was elected as the prime minister.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Elections in 1993 brought Benazir Bhutto back as the prime minister. However, the party was once again dismissed by the president, Farooq Leghari, in 1996.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In 1997, midterm elections were held and Nawaz Sharif became the prime minister of Pakistan for the second time.]]></text>

<!-- Caption -->

<text><![CDATA[Mohammed Ali Jinnah]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Liaquat Ali Khan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Mausoleum of Quaid-e-Azam Mohammed Ali Jinnah]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Liaquat Ali Khan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Iskander Mirza]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Ayub Khan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Mohammad Yahya Khan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sheikh Mujibur Rahman]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Zulfikar Ali Bhutto]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sheikh Mujib]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[General Zia-ul-Haq]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Zulfikar Ali Bhutto]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Zia-ul-Haq]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Benazir Bhutto]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Nawaz Sharif]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Pervez Musharraf]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Benazir Bhutto]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Asif Ali Zardari]]></text>


<text><![CDATA[In October 1999, the government of Nawaz Sharif was dismissed by General Pervez Musharraf who took over the government.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Benazir Bhutto was tragically killed on 27 December 2007.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In 2008, Asif Ali Zardari, the co-chairman of the PPP, became the president of Pakistan.]]></text>





</data>
</framexml>