<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<framexml>
<data>

<!-- 1M2 -->
<text><![CDATA[<B>Pakistan and her neighbours</B>]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[Pakistan is situated in the continent of Asia.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The latitudinal extent of Pakistan is 24°N and 37°N.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The longitudinal extent of Pakistan is 61°E and 76°E.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[Pakistan shares its border with Afghanistan and Iran in the west.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Pakistan shares border with China and India in the north and east.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In the south, Pakistan has an 800 km coastline along the Arabian Sea.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[Iran is a country of deserts and plateaus surrounded by mountains.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Iran was earlier known as Persia.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The capital of Iran is Tehran.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[The population of Iran consists of Persians, Turks, Kurds, Armenians, and Arabs.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Iran is an agricultural country. Wheat, rice, tobacco, and sugar beet are grown in Iran.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Iran has 10% of the world's oil reserves and also has natural gas, copper, iron ore, lead, and precious stones.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In 1979, Ayatollah Khomeini took over the government in an Islamic Revolution.]]></text>


<text><![CDATA[Afghanistan is a mountainous country with cold winters and dry summers.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The capital of Afghanistan is Kabul.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The population of Afghanistan is made up of ethnic groups like Pashtuns, Uzbeks, and Tajiks.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[All major land routes from the Middle East to the subcontinent pass through Afghanistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Afghanistan became a strong country under Ahmed Shah Durrani in 1747.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[In recent years, Afghanistan has suffered a lot of destruction due to political unrest.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[China is a very large country compared to Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Pakistan is separated from China by the Karakoram range.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[Beijing is the capital city of China.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Mandarin Chinese is the official language of China.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[China is mainly an agricultural country.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[In 1949, the Chinese Communist Party came to power under the leadership of Mao Zedong.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The communist party founded the new People's Republic of China.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[India is a large country situated to the east of Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Pakistan and India shared a common history until 1947.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[India is basically an agricultural country.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[India has developed many large industries.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[The great river Ganges flows through the northern plains of India.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The Deccan Plateau covers most of the southern part of India.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[New Delhi is the capital of India.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Hindi and English are the official languages of India.]]></text>

<text><![CDATA[Pakistan shares a good relationship with other Muslim countries of the world.]]></text>







<!-- Caption -->

<text><![CDATA[Ayatollah Khomeini ]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[A school in Afghanistan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Ahmed Shah Durrani]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The Great Wall of China]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Karakoram Range]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Beijing Botanical Garden]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Mandarin Chinese]]></text>


<text><![CDATA[River Ganges]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Deccan Plateau]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[New Delhi]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Hindi]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[English]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Mao Zedong]]></text>











</data>
</framexml>