<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<framexml>
<data>

<!-- 1M2 -->
<text><![CDATA[<B>Water and irrigation</B>]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Although Pakistan is a dry country, some great rivers flow through our nation.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[To ensure that crops get a steady supply of water, farmers have to irrigate their fields.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Canal irrigation involves digging water channels from rivers or lakes to agricultural fields.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Dams and barrages are constructed over rivers to divert water through canals to fields.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[All large rivers of Pakistan have canals running off them.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Warsak, Mangla, Tarbela, Bolan, and Rawal are some of the famous dams of Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Shaduf and Charsa are two ancient methods of irrigation.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[A Shaduf consists of a long pole with a bucket suspended by a rope at one end and a weight at the other.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[A Charsa consists of a bucket attached to a pulley.  Animals are used to pull the water to the surface.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Persian wheel is another method of irrigation.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[A Persian wheel consists of a number of buckets attached to a wheel. The wheel is rotated by an animal.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[As the wheel rotates, the buckets dip into the water below and come up with water.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The water is tipped into a small channel connected to the fields.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Karez is an underground water tunnel used for irrigation.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The water from Karez comes to the surface and led to the fields and orchards.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The use of tube wells is a modern method of irrigation.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Water is pumped up from deep below the ground and used for irrigation.]]></text>




<!-- Caption -->

<text><![CDATA[Water for irrigation is obtained mainly from wells and canals.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Canal irrigation]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Dam]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Barrage]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Warsak Dam]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Shaduf]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Charsa]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Shaduf]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Charsa]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Persian wheel]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Karez]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Indus]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Ravi]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Jhelum]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Chenab]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sutlej]]></text>











</data>
</framexml>