<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<framexml>
<data>

<!-- 1M2 -->
<text><![CDATA[<B>The struggle for independence</B>]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[During the British rule in the subcontinent, the officers of the army were all British and the soldiers Hindus, Muslims, or Sikhs.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The soldiers revolted in 1857 due to the introduction of controversial bullets greased with animal fat.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The battle fought between the soldiers against the British is called the <i>War of Independence</i>.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The soldiers were defeated and the Mughal King Bahadur Shah Zafar was sent into exile in Rangoon.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Some educated people started the Indian National Congress in 1885.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The National Congress became powerful under the leadership of Mohandas Gandhi.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Some Muslim leaders formed the All India Muslim League in 1906.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The Muslims believed that if the British left India the Hindus would take control of the country.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The Muslims were inspired by leaders like Sir Syed Ahmed Khan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sir Syed advocated that the Muslims educate themselves and improve their situation.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Leaders of Muslim league.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sir Mohammad Iqbal put forward the idea of a separate state for the Muslims at Allahabad in 1930.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The most famous Muslim leader at that time was a lawyer named Mohammed Ali Jinnah.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[After a long struggle and many discussions with the British, two countries were formed&#8212;India and Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The areas where the majority of the population was Muslim became Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[The remaining parts became India or <i>Bharat</i>.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Pakistan became an independent country on 14 August 1947.]]></text>

<!-- Caption -->
<text><![CDATA[Sir Syed Ahmed Khan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sir Syed Ahmed Khan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Allama Iqbal]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Nawab Viqarul Mulk]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Maulana Mohammad Ali Jauhar]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Liaquat Ali Khan]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sir Mohammad Iqbal]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Mohammed Ali Jinnah]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[India (Bharat)]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Nehru with Gandhi]]></text>

<cptn><![CDATA[The War of Independence 1857]]></cptn>
<cptn><![CDATA[Aligarh Muslim University founded by Sir Syed Ahmed Khan]]></cptn>
<cptn><![CDATA[Bahadur Shah Zafar]]></cptn>



</data>
</framexml>