<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<framexml>
<data>

<!-- 1M2 -->
<text><![CDATA[<B>Agriculture in Pakistan </B>]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Agriculture is the major occupation of the people of Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Punjab is the most fertile and agriculturally developed region of Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Almost 70% of the cultivated land in Pakistan is used to grow food crops.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Kharif crops]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Rabi crops]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Crops that we grow for food are called food crops.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Wheat is a major food crop and a staple food in Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Rice is the second most cultivated crop in Pakistan. It grows well in warm and very moist places.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Millet is a hardy crop that can grow in poor soil with very little water.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Pulses and oilseeds are some other food crops grown in Pakistan.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Crops that we grow for commercial purposes are called cash crops.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Cotton is one of the major cash crops of Pakistan and its leading export.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sugar cane is the second most important cash crop of Pakistan after cotton.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Tobacco is another important cash crop. It is also exported to other countries.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Livestock is an important sector of agriculture. Although tractors have become common, some farmers still use bullocks to plough their fields.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Pakistan is one of the world's largest producers of milk.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Most of the meat we eat comes from buffaloes, cows, and goats.]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sheep and goats are reared in hilly regions, plains, plateaus, and deserts for meat, wool, and skins.]]></text>

<!-- Caption -->
<text><![CDATA[Cotton]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Rice]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Maize]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Millet]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Wheat]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Gram]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Rapeseed]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Mustard]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Food crop]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Wheat]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Rice]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Millet]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Maize]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Pulses]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Oil seeds]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Cotton]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Sugar cane]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Tobacco]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Livestock]]></text>
<text><![CDATA[Milk]]></text>

</data>
</framexml>